# SOLAYMAN HOSSAIN EMON

# **Deep Learning Enthusiast**

- **L** +880 1521220812
- @ solayman.emon07@gmail.com
- https://github.com/Solayman-Emon
- § 51 SSC Road Mahuttuli, Bangshal, Dhaka, Bangladesh.



#### **OBJECTIVE**

To utilize my technical skills for the growth of the organization as well as to enhance my knowledge about new and emerging trends in the IT sector. Passionate in research works based on Deep Learning. Wanted to boost up my career as a AI (Artificial Intelligence) researcher.

#### **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering (CSE)

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology (AUST)

CGPA: 3.479 / 4.00 (Estimated Average upto 4th Year 1st Semester)

Sept 2016 - ongoing

◆ Dhaka, Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC) in Science

Dhaka College

GPA: 5.00 / 5.00

Ohaka, Bangladesh

### **EXPERIENCE**

Research & Development Intern

**Psycure Organization** 

July 2020 - Ongoing

P Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Freelancer

Freelancer.com

Oct 2018 - Ongoing

**♀** Freelance

Sub-Executive at Department of Olympiad

Dhaka College Science Club (DCSC)

**#** July 2013 - Sept 2015

Ohaka, Bangladesh

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Research Work (Ongoing)

Thesis Title: "Automatic Video Summarization from Cricket Videos with Deep Learning"

Supervisor: Shoeb Mohammad Shahriar

Assistant Professor, Department of CSE

### **AREA OF INTEREST**

Artificial Intelligence Deep Learning Computer Vision Computational Biology & Respective Fields

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Language
Python, C++, MATLAB, ASP.NET, SQL, PL/SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS

IDE Colaboratory, Codeblocks, Microsoft Visual Studio, Atom

Database
 My SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle 10 g

Miscellaneous
 Microsoft Office, LaTeX, Photoshop

# LINGUISTIC PROFICIENCY

Bengali - Native proficiency

English – Limited working proficiency

### CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Participated in Intra Aust Programming Contest Fall 2016, Spring 2017 & Fall 2017.
- Selected for ITEE (Information-Technology Engineers Examination) Training Program Organized by Department of CSE, AUST.
- Member at AUST Innovation & Design Club (AUSTIDC).
- Volunteer at Department of Olympiad in 4th Farm Fresh Dhaka College Science Club (DCSC) National Science Expo 2014.

# MASSIVE OPEN ONLINE COURSE (MOOC)

- **■** Coursera Deep Learning Specialization course offered by deeplearning.ai
- **■** Coursera TensorFlow in Practice Specialization course offered by deeplearning.ai

# REFERENCES

Prof. Dr. Kazi A kalpoma

Professor & Head, Department of CSE

Director, ICT Center

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology

**U** +880 1819127854

▼ kalpoma@aust.edu

#### **Shoeb Mohammad Shahriar**

Assistant Professor, Department of CSE Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology

**U** +880 1917256784

■ shoeb.cse@aust.edu

Please visit: https://solayman-cs.github.io

